In the 11th century,
11世紀。
the invasion by Denmark's army
and the Vikings
デンマーク軍およびヴァイキングによる侵攻は
continued to intensify.
激化の一途をたどっていた
ENGLAND 1012 AD
In October,
そして10月。
the attacks, which had continued for several years,
数年間にわたって継続された攻撃は
reached a turning point.
転換点を迎える
VICINITY OF JELLING DENMARK
KING SWEYN'S ESTATE
Are you telling me
to withdraw my troops from England?
ではイングランドから兵を退かれると？
We're not withdrawing. We're letting them rest.
退くのではない。休めるのだ。
Marching in the winter weakens them.
冬の行軍は兵力を浪費する
Let the soldiers rest.
派兵した軍にも英気を養わせよ
Yes, sir. As you wish.
は。仰せのとおりに
The summer.
夏だ…
We're going to strike next summer.
来年の夏には大攻勢をかける。
I, too, shall lead an army in battle.
余も兵を率いて陣頭に立つ
So, suddenly we get a break?
いきなり休みかぁ。
ENGLAND COAST
DANISH ARMY BASE
I want to go home.
郷に帰りてぇよ
We don't need those pirates for now, either.
海賊連中も当分用なしだな
I thought I'd be able to earn a lot this year.
…今年も稼げると思ったのによー
We can't do anything,
now that the army is staying put.
正規の兵が動かねぇんじゃな
This is why I hate being a hired hand.
これだから雇われ仕事はなぁ～
What's Askeladd going to do?
どうするつもりだぁ？アシェラッドは
Askeladd.
アシェラッド。
It'd be a shame to spend all winter like this.
このまま冬を越すのはちと寂しくねーか？
And we already raided all the good villages.
めぼしい村は平らげちまったしよぉ
True.
だよなぁ
What are you going to do?
どうするつもりだ？
We can't do anything about it.
どーするもこーするも…
We're going to do what the birds do.
渡り鳥と一緒さ。
We'll go to where the food is.
餌のある所に移動するだけよ
KINGDOM OF FRANCE
VICINITY OF LOIRE RIVER
Don't just stand there.
グズグズするなぁ！
They have a ram.
ラムだぁ！
Bring the crossbowmen.
弩兵集まれぇ！
One. Two.
せーのぉっ！
Alternate fire with two groups.
二隊交互で斉射だ！
Aim.
かまえ！
Fire.
てぇ！
It's no good. Retreat.
だめだ！退けぇーっ！
It looks like the Franks are fighting
amongst themselves.
フランク人同士の小競り合いか…
The fort's defended by only a few men.
砦側は少数。
The attackers have 800.
攻め手は800ってとこか。
I can't believe they attacked the fort head-on.
あの砦に正面からぶつかるとはなぁ
So, this is the local clan's headquarters.
土豪の本拠地ってとこか。
How about it? Doesn't it smell like treasure?
どうだ？お宝の匂いがプンプンしねぇか？
So, that's what you're after.
これが狙いってわけか。
Let's do it, Askeladd.
やるか。アシェラッド
We'll side with the attackers.
攻め手につくぞ。
Let's smash open the treasure chest,
and take everything inside.
宝箱をブッ壊して中身をゴッソリいただこう
All right.
よっしゃ！
I was wondering why we came to the boonies.
こぉんなド田舎でどうするつもりかと思ったけど、
You're amazing, Askeladd.
さすがアシェラッドだぜ！
Your predictions were spot-on.
やっぱ首領の読みは間違いねぇ！
Let's make up our loss from England.
イングランドで稼げなかった分、取り戻すぜ！
Okay, Thorfinn.
そんじゃトルフィン！
You're up.
へっ。出番だよ
We're going to war.
参戦だ
NORMANNI
We're going to war.
参戦だ。
Make contact with their leader.
攻め手の親分にわたりをつけといで。
Give him this message:
口上はこうだ
"You're terrible at battle.
貴殿の戦はァヘタだっ！
I can't stand watching you.
見るに堪えん。
Therefore, my men will help you.
よって我が兵団お助け申す。
This is a once-in-a-lifetime offer.
千載一遇わたりに船。
I shall lead you to victory, no matter what.
必ずや汝らを勝利へ導くであろう
Once the fort falls, we will take half of the spoils.
砦が陥ちた暁には戦利品の半分を所望する。
We shall attack again tomorrow morning."
明朝再び突撃されよ。
After you deliver the message, stay in their camp,
and observe the situation.
伝えたら奴らの兵営に残って状況を見張れ。
Got it? Then go.
わかったら行け
What's wrong?
どうした？
Go, Thorfinn.
行けよトルフィン
Do you have any idea how many people I've killed?
これまでにどれだけ殺したと思ってる。
I went scouting,
斥候にも出たし、
and I also brought up the rear.
しんがりも務めた。
I've accomplished enough.
手柄は十分に立てた。
But you...
なのに…てめぇは…！
What? You want a reward?
なんだよ。ほうびが欲しいのか？
If you close the deal, I'll give you three gold pieces.
交渉成立なら金貨3枚くれてやるよ。
I swear in the name of Tyr.
ティール神に誓ってね
Don't test me.
ざけんな…
How long do you plan to keep running away?
いつまで逃げ回ってるつもりだ…！
I'm so scared.
ウホホッこわい！
I was just joking.
からかっただけだって。
But you know...
だがなぁ…
You'd have to bring me at least one head with a helmet,
if you want that.
それならカブト首の1つくらい、
とってこなきゃあならんだろうぜ
He never changes.
相変わらずだな…
Are you sure it's okay
to let him handle the negotiation?
でもいいのか？大事な交渉任せちまって
Soldiers are short-tempered
when they're weak.
劣勢の兵は気が立ってる。
They might kill the messenger,
before the negotiations start. It happens all the time.
交渉の前に殺されるなんざよくある話さ。
Who cares if we lose some kid that follows us?
拾ったガキなら惜しくはないだろ？
What are you doing, kid?
なんじゃア！わっぱ！
This is no place for a kid.
ガキの来る所じゃねぇぞ、コラァ！
I'm a messenger.
軍使だ。
Is there anyone who can speak Norse?
ノルド語を話せる奴はいるか？
What's wrong with you? What language is that?
なんだこのガキ？何語だ？
He's not a Frank.
フランク人じゃねえな
Is he a spy from the fort?
砦の奴らのスパイか？
Secure him.
ま、捕らえとけ
I'm a messenger.
オレは軍使だ！
Is there anyone who can speak Norse?
ノルド語を話せる奴はいるか！？
You want half of the spoils?
戦利品の半分をよこせだとォ？
You mercenaries. Don't push your luck.
傭兵風情が図に乗りおって！
"You want half of the spoils?
Don't push your luck."
You're pretty confident in yourself.
たいした自信だな、ええ？
Normanni kid.
ノルマンニの小僧よ
Normanni?
ノルマンニ…
Those people from the north attacking England?
イングランドを荒らし回っている北の民か
"Those people from the north attacking England?"
Even a kid can see it.
小僧でもわかる。
If you keep attacking the front gate,
your men are just going to die.
正門ばかり攻めても兵が死ぬだけだ。
Their defenses are weak on the lake.
湖の防備は薄い。
We're going to attack there.
オレたちはそこを叩く
Your plan is ill-considered.
浅知恵だな
The river that leads to the lake gets steeper upstream.
湖に至る川は上るにつれ勾配がきつくなる。
There's even a waterfall.
あまつさえ滝もあるのだ
Our ship sunk downstream.
我々の船も下流で往生しておる。
That's what would happen
if you attacked from the lake.
湖から攻撃せぬのはそういうことだ
"That's what would happen
if you attacked from the lake."
Then do you want to turn down my offer?
断るか？この話。
Then Askeladd and his hundred men are going
to join the defenders in the fort.
ならばアシェラッドの兵100人は砦側と手を結ぶ
He'll do the same thing if I die too.
オレが死んだ場合も同じだ。
If I don't signal that the deal has been closed,
商談成立の合図がない場合、
you're going to make enemies
of a hundred fierce men from the Northern Sea.
北海の猛者100人がお前の敵になる
Very well.
よかろう
Your Highness.
閣下！
But...
だが！
if you're lying, I'm going to cut off your head.
貴様の言葉が偽りであればその首を斬り落とす！
If you're telling the truth,
then in the name of Jesus Christ,
まことであればイエス・キリストの名において
I'll share my bread equally.
パンを等しく分かち合おう
"I'll share my bread equally."
Give me back my dagger.
オレの短剣を返してくれ。
It's a memento from my father.
親父の形見なんだ
It's Thorfinn's signal.
トルフィンからの知らせだ。
One high arrow, and two low arrows.
高く1本。低く2本…
Let's hurry.
急ぐぜ。
Let's cross the pass before the moon rises.
月が昇りきる前に峠を越えるぞ
We're stuck guarding the ship the whole time.
ずっと船の護衛かよ。
I want to fight too.
オレも戦いてえなぁ
Damn that fat general.
クソッ。あのデブ将軍め！
Over there.
あそこか？
It's a dragon!
竜だぁぁぁーっ！
It's on the mountain.
山の上だ！
A dragon?
竜が
You said, the dragon climbed the mountain?
竜が山をのぼったじゃと？
Yes. Last night,
the soldiers guarding the ship all reported they saw it.
はい。昨夜、船の守備兵全員が見たとの報告が
I see.
ほぉ…
It's a bad omen, Your Highness.
凶兆です閣下
I want to see it too.
ワシも一度見てみたいもんじゃ
Kid.
小僧！
Your friends haven't come yet.
貴様の仲間来ぬではないか。
"I want to see it too."
The sun is already up.
もう陽が昇ってしまったぞ
"The sun is already up."
Just attack, you fat-ass.
いいから突撃しろデブ
You'll understand soon.
すぐにわかる
You said something mean just now, didn't you?
今なんか悪口言っただろ。
It looks like our entertainment for tonight is going
to be cutting off your head.
どうやら貴様の首は今宵の余興になりそうだな！
Forward march.
前進用意！
Forward.
前進ーっ！
Attack.
突撃ーっ！
Oh, no. It's started.
いかん。始まっちまった！
We're late. Bastards.
出遅れたぞ！野郎ども！
Put your heart into it.
気合いを入れろ！
The battlefield is waiting.
戦場が待ってるぜ！
It'll be the same every time.
何度来ても同じだぁ！
Come on.
ああんもうっ！
Put a bridge on the west side too.
西側にもハシゴをかけろ！
I don't care how many men we lose.
犠牲を厭うな！
Hey. Which one is their leader?
おい。敵の大将はどいつだ？
The one with the feather on his helmet.
羽飾りのついたカブトが見えるだろう。
It's him.
アイツだ
A head with a helmet.
カブト首
You bastard.
貴様ッ！
He was lying. Kill him.
やはりウソか！コロセーッ！
Kill the kid.
小僧を殺せ！
You bastard.
お～の～れぇぇぇ！
You let the kid escape.
You haven't captured the fort.
小僧は逃がすわ砦は陥ちぬわ！
What's wrong with you guys?
どうなってるんじゃこの軍はーっ！
You're thinking you'll go home,
once the snow falls.
雪が降れば帰れると思うとんじゃろ！
That's not going to happen.
そうはいかんぞ！
You're not going home until the fort is captured.
砦が陥ちるまでは絶対に…
What?
な…！？
Heave-ho.
よっこらぁせーっ！
Row. Full speed ahead.
漕げェ！全速力ゥ！
Whoever gets there first gets twice as much.
一番乗りは倍の分け前だ！
Put your heart into it.
気合い入れろ！
I see.
そうか！
Those were friendly forces.
All troops, forward. Don't stop until the fort falls.
あれは友軍じゃ！全軍進めーっ！
砦を陥とすのだ！
Never imagined they'd carry their ship over the pass.
担いで峠越えをするとは…
Don't hesitate.
うろたえるなっ！
Eighty men from the right wing,
go to the boat landing.
右翼の80人は船着き場へ行け！
Crossbowmen, this way.
弩隊、来い！
Is that all you got?
お粗末だぜ
The lake's not a barrier.
湖側は防壁どころか
It's a shallow pond that makes for a perfect attack.
絶好の浅瀬なんだもんよ！
Great. We're going in.
いよぉし！ブッ込むぞ！
What? They pierced my shield,
even though they're so far away.
なんだァ！？この距離で盾を貫きやがった！
They got Olov.
ウーロフが殺られたぞ！
Askeladd.
アシェラッド！
Crossbowmen?
弩か。
We're going to take a few losses.
多少損害が出るな
This is the perfect chance.
今なら格好の的だ！
Fire as much as you can before they land.
上陸される前にできるだけ…
A child?
子供…？
What?
あれ？
They stopped attacking?
攻撃がやんだ？
Maybe they ran out of arrows.
矢が切れたのかな？
Men. Prepare to land.
上陸用意だ野郎ども！
This is our chance.
チャンスだ！
-Oh, no.
-Kill him.
しまった！
殺せ！
-This is for the captain.
-Damn.
隊長の仇！
-That kid's crazy.
-Get him.
たたっ斬れ！
逃がすな！
Go. Storm them.
いけぇ！なだれ込め！
All right. Go on a rampage.
よぉし！暴れまくれ！
Holding the gate's too hard for these guys.
門の方は大丈夫なのかね？コイツら
Hurry up, and kill them all, guys.
ちゃちゃっと殺れよー野郎ども
One. Two.
せェェのぉおっ！
Those Normannis are crazy.
なんて奴らだ…ノルマンニ…
That fortress was no match
against my military tactics.
ワシの用兵術にかかってはこんな砦イチコロよ！
The captain of the fortress defense died in battle.
砦の守備隊長は戦死しました。
The soldiers said, a kid did it.
敗兵の話によると子供の仕業とか
That kid?
あの小僧か！？
Never underestimate a Normanni.
侮れんなノルマンニ…
If I send him back now,
he's going to become an enemy.
このまま帰しては我らの敵となるやも…
What shall we do?
いかがいたしましょう
Those guys came over the pass, right?
連中は峠を越えてきた。
They'll probably go back the same way,
carrying the ship.
帰りも船を担いでいくだろう。
That's when we'll attack.
そこを叩く。
A sailor on land is like a baby.
陸に上がった船乗りなど赤子同然よ
Your Highness.
閣下ーっ！
I have a message for General Jabbathe.
ジャバザ将軍に！ご報告ー！
What is it? Tell me.
なんだ？申せ
The treasure room...
ほっ、宝物庫が！
Where's my treasure?
ワシの宝…は？
They also plundered the church
and the houses of all the leaders.
有力者の家や教会も荒らされております！
They took everything.
金目のものは何もかも…
What?
なっ…だっ…
I see.
あ、そっ…
I have a message for the leader of the Franks.
フランク人の長に申し上げーーる！
What?
As for your half of the spoils,
戦利品の半分として、
you get victory,
貴殿は勝利を。
and we get the treasure.
我らは財宝を！
You're fine with that, right?
文句あるまいな
I think we're being quite generous here, you know.
これでも謙虚な方だと思うぜ。
We let you have the fort, after all.
砦はくれてやるんだからなァ
-You bastards.
-Oh, no.
おにょれぇぇぇ！
いかん！
-They'll descend the waterfall.
-Savages.
奴ら滝を下る気だ！
-Get the boats.
-You pirates.
船を出せ！それが…
-All boats in the fort have been destroyed.
-You greedy beasts.
砦にあった船は全て壊されてしまいまして
You scammers.
サギ師～！
You country bumpkins.
田舎モ～ン！
あ～？
I can't understand French.
フランク語はわからんな～
Now then, shall we call it a night?
さてと。おいとまするか
Thorfinn hasn't returned.
トルフィンがまだだぜ
Oh, really?
あらホント。
Oh, well. I bet he's dead anyway.
まぁ、どーせ死んでる死んでる。
Now there's more treasure for us.
分け前増えてよかったじゃん
You're alive?
生きてたのか
You're tough, kid. Did you get hurt?
しぶといガキだな
ケガはねぇか？
Askeladd.
アシェラッド！
It's the captain's head.
大将首だ
Well, did you cut it off?
へぇ。とったのか
You promised.
約束だ。
I won't let you say no.
イヤとは言わせねぇ
I, warrior from Iceland, son of Thors, Thorfinn,
アイスランドの戦士、トールズの子トルフィン。
in the name of my father's sword,
challenge you, Askeladd, to a duel.
我が父の剣にかけてアシェラッドに決闘を申し込む。
To avenge my father's death.
貴君は我が父の仇であるがゆえに
-Hey.
-He wants to duel now?
おいおいこんな時もかよ
He's got guts.
よくやるなぁ…
I, son of Olaf, Askeladd,
ウォラフの子アシェラッド。
in the name of Artorius, my ancestor,
我が祖アルトリウスの名にかけて
accept your challenge, Thorfinn.
トルフィンの挑戦を受けよう。
However...
…が、
ask me again later.
後にしてくれ！
We're getting out of here now.
今はこっから逃げるぜ！
Row, men.
漕げ！野郎ども！
If you don't hurry up, they'll capture the river.
グズグズしてると川を押さえられるぞ！
You bastard. Don't play the fool with me.
おい！てめぇ！ふざけんなーっ！
Who cares if there's a dragon?
竜がなんだっつーんだ！
I'm not scared.
怖かねぇ！
Right, right.
んだんだ！
But you know...
んでもヨォ…
It's here!
Goodbye.
さらばだーっ！
Franks.
フランクの衆よーっ！
-Let's go home.
-We struck it big.
家～っ！
大儲けだーっ！
We'll survive the winter.
冬が越せるーっ！
Yeah.
っしゃあ！